Roger Vilà

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

rogervila@me.com

linkedin.com/in/rogervilacamon

github.com/rogervila

+34666148225



rogervila.es



@_rogervila

Summary

I have worked for almost 10 years as a software developer. Currently, I work as a Senior Software Analyst at K-LAGAN, where I lead a team of four developers, building strategic solutions that are helping business to achieve new goals from different technical perspectives (DevOps, Web, Big Data and RPA).

I am deeply passionate about finding technical challenges that allows business to discover new value that helps to grow up.

Previously, I worked as a freelancer on different start-ups placed in Barcelona, developing specific projects, mostly web based, for third-party companies like Coca-cola, HP and GFT among others.

If you catch me outside of work, I'm an amateur hiker that loves to find new routes:)

I also like meeting new people over a cup of coffee. Feel free to reach out at rogervila@me.com or DM on Twitter @ rogervila.

Competencies: PHP (I work with Laravel mainly), JS (Vue and React), Python, DevOPS tools (Docker + Swarm, Jenkins) and Databases (SQL, NoSQL and Graph, mainly Neo4J)

P.S. You may see my Open source projects and blog posts on my personal website - www.rogervila.es

Experience

Senior Programming Analyst

K-LAGAN

Aug 2017 - Present (4 years 5 months +)

As a Software analyst I leverage different project functionalities across shared micro-services based on Docker.

We use Laravel for API integrations and background tasks, and Python for data processing and RPA tools.

My main task is to lead technically a team of four developers (sometimes the team works with other remote teams from other world locations), to ensure code quality and functionality integration.

www.k-lagan.com

Full Stack Developer

HEALTH DATALINE EUROPE SA

Mar 2017 - Aug 2017 (6 months)

As a Full-Stack Developer I was in charge of adapting the client eCommerce websites for mobile by creating new front-end versions for specific devices (mobile and tablet mainly) based on Onsen UI.

To achieve that goal, I was required to create internal APIs to retrieve data from different data sources on the backend.

www.toopharm.com www.healthdataline.com



CEO & Co-Founder

SeeDoCare

Oct 2015 - Aug 2017 (1 year 11 months)

With my colleague Jon (https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonromerolinero), we started a business based on totally personalized web software solutions for customers, with some small to medium companies.

On 2017, the lack of big clients plus the job offers we found on the market made us take the decision to close the business and work full-time for other companies, which resulted on less work hours and more salary.

Software Developer

Emotion Experience

Nov 2016 - Feb 2017 (4 months)

Emotion Experience is specialized on interactive spaces where the public can interact with the brands directly.

I was part of the team that creates specific software for each action, working with LED displays and interactive panels.

I was hired to work on a specific setup for GFT which was called "GFT Lab" (https:// www.lightsoundgroup.com/portfolio/gft-lab/)

www.lightsoundgroup.com



(c) Web Developer

(caravelo (

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Caravelo offers solutions for travel companies.

I was hired to work on a specific product for Volaris Airline company called "Volado Volaris", which offered cheap trips with few hours in advance for planes with empty seats.

My main task was to develop all the front-end Website.

www.caravelo.com

Web Developer

Apr 2015 - Nov 2015 (8 months)

I worked on the spanish version of the siQuri eCommerce, and also handled the maintenance of the Company wordpress blog.

www.siquri.com

Web Development Instructor

CIPSA Escuela Superior Informática Profesional Barcelona Bilbao CURSOS & MASTERS

Oct 2014 - Apr 2015 (7 months)

After finishing the Full Stack Web Design and Programming Master I was hired as an instructor for that master.

My main task was to guide my students to grow up as developers, starting with a very simple HTML landing page and finishing the course with a big full-stack project.

www.cipsa.net

Web Developer

Mediterrani Food

May 2013 - Jun 2014 (1 year 2 months)

My main task was to grow up the company influence in the Social Media by developing and maintaining a WordPress site and publishing posts and events on it.

www.twitter.com/mediterranifood

Education

CIPSA Barcelona

Master's degree, Web Development Master 2013 - 2014

Conservatori Liceu

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Music Theory and Composition 2010 - 2014
Music Theory and Composition

Sibelius-Akatemia - Sibelius-Akademin

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Composition 2012 - 2013 Piano, Composition & Electronic Music Education.

Conservatori Liceu

Associate's degree, Music Performance, General 2008 - 2010 Piano & Music education.